#### SARAFINE JEPTUM

Nairobi City, Lang'ata.

Tel: +254 708 293875

Email: sarafinelagat@gmail.com

#### **CAREER PROFILE**

An intricate IT professional with vast understanding of various related IT elements. I am committed to finding innovative solutions to a variety of IT problems, such as security, database management and technical troubleshooting. I can offer your organization exemplary support with network administration, effective project management and increased system performance. I am an agile learner with the ability to relate well with colleagues and contribute to the improvement of IT related systems. Highlights of my experience include; provision of technical support to users for IT related hardware and software, managing workstation images for multiple operating system (OS) environments, WatchGuard firewall management and network security & access control, supervising support engineering staff and end users.

#### **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

Bsc Information Technology - Multimedia University of Kenya; 2014 – 2018.

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education – St. Elizabeth Girl's Secondary School; 2010 – 2013.

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education - Cheplelachbei Primary school; 2002 – 2009.

## **KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES**

- **Network Administration:** Adept at network configuration, installation and troubleshooting and investigating internet and other reported service issues and providing appropriate solution within the scope of service level agreement.
- **Troubleshooting and maintenance:** Adept at maintaining computer network infrastructure and liaise with external service providers to ensure optimal uptime and best service and enforce an up-to date systems backup.
- **System Administration:** Ability to handle Server configuration, Desktop administration, Software and hardware maintenance.
- **Cyber security:** Ability to solve any system vulnerabilities a system may have by ensuring that a system is secure, stable and prepared to fight off any security attack. Well adept with staying up-to date with security updates e.g., Anti-viruses.
- **Operating Systems:** Knowledge of operating systems for example Windows XP, 2007/2008/2010 DOS, UNIX, Linux; Windows Server 2003/2008/2012/2016.

- **Technical expertise:** Experienced in providing technical expertise for IT network design, implementation, optimization, repairing and upgrade.
- Communication Skills: Capability to relate well with employees and clients who need help with navigating their systems considering that every employee has their own level of computer competency.
- **Learning agility:** Ability to quickly learn from others and teach myself upcoming systems and software upgrades and updates.

## **WORK HISTORY**

## **Stepwise Company (February 2021 to date)**

Optical Character Recognition(OCR) proofreading.

## FCR Solutions Limited (October 18th 2021, to 30th March)

Data Processing Agent filling in the clients forms on a daily basis and reporting to Compliance Manager and Head of Compliance.

IT Support & Systems & Network Security Administrator, OS LABS Company Ltd - Subcontracted to Mwalimu National Sacco, Risk and Insurance Brokers Ltd. (March 2021-18<sup>th</sup> June 2021)

## **Duties and Responsibilities**

- Adding employees to Microsoft 365 platform.
- Administration of azure active directory on Microsoft 365.
- Mapping Microsoft shared drives to individual PCs.
- Creating and administering email accounts in Microsoft 365 mail server.
- Setting up Google sync with outlook.
- Providing technical support to users for IT related hardware and software.
- Reporting to the IT Manager and seek for task approvals.
- Laying cables for network connections.
- Windows Operating System and other software installation on laptops and Desktops.
- Continually monitoring, reporting and improvement of ICT Endpoint Systems and Services in coverage, service efficiency, effectiveness per established key performance indicator (KPIs)

#### Intern,

## Kenya Power & Lightning company, Donholm Nairobi. (January 2019 – June 2019)

## **Duties and responsibilities**

- Data Networking and Telecommunication that is Routers, Switches, Network cables Termination and Router configuration.
- Troubleshooting LAN network issues.
- Installation of network printers.
- Performing preventive maintenance.
- Domain errors that is migrating a PC/Laptop from one domain to another.
- Providing technical support to users for IT related hardware and software problems.
- Performed System software installation and updated them.

#### Attaché,

# Kenya Power & Lightning company, Donholm Nairobi. (May 2016 – August 2016) and (September 2018-November 2018)

### **Duties and responsibilities:**

- Performed IT user support tasks.
- Troubleshooting LAN network issues.
- Attended Linux training sessions organized by the supervisor.
- Carried out hardware maintenance as per the directives of the supervisor.
- Performed System software installation and updated them.
- Printer installation and connection Both Local and Network printers.
- Data Networking and Telecommunication that is Routers, Switches, Network cables Termination and Router configuration.
- Domain errors that are migrating a PC/Laptop from one domain to another, trust relationship errors between the workstation and primary domain.
- Preventive maintenance.
- Basics of computing and how a computer works in terms of software and hardware.
- Microsoft Exchange and Active Directory Outlook, Outlook Express Internet services (mail, web, anti-spam).

# REFEREES.

Benard Juma Onyach

System administrator,

Oslabs Limited.

Tel: +254 716 824022

Email: onyachbenard@gmail.com

Mr. Bernard Okuku

Lecturer,

Multimedia University of Kenya

Tel: +254 722 675145

Email: bernardokuku@gmail.com